最近在研究什么呢
So, what are you working on these days?
我在研究单细胞生物
I'm studying one-celled organisms
试图从它们身上找到
to try and find the neurochemicals
引发羞愧感的神经化学物质
that lead to the feeling of shame.
单细胞生物会有什么需要感到羞耻的事啊
What would a one-celled organism have to be embarrassed about?
跟人类一样  车震完没穿内衣裤下车
Same as all of us, getting out of a car without underwear.
说到内衣
Speaking of underwear,
我有件挺有意思的事
I have some interesting news...
如果是华仔偶尔会穿你的内衣
Okay, if it's sometimes Howie wears yours,
那莱纳德已经告诉过我们了
Leonard already told us.
他只是在搞笑
He was being funny.
我挺确定
I'm pretty sure.
总之  我受邀参与一篇关于加州
Anyway, I was asked to be a part of a magazine article
最性感的50名女性科学家的杂志专题
about the 50 sexiest female scientists in California.
挺酷的吧
Isn't that cool?
我觉得很恶心
I think it's awful.
你怎么会这么说
Why would you say that?
伯纳黛特是一位成功的微生物学家
Bernadette is a successful microbiologist.
人们应该赞美她的科研成果  而非长相
She should be celebrated for her achievements, not her looks.
参与这种杂志专题  人们会怎么想
I mean, what kind of message does that send?
人们大概会想  "快看这童颜科学家的巨乳"
I think the message is-- "Check out the rack on that scientist."
为什么就不能被认为是智慧与美貌并存的呢
Why can't someone be thought of as both smart and pretty?
我只是不觉得一位职场女性需要靠
I just don't think a professional woman should have
展现自己女性象征来获得成功
to flaunt her sexuality in order to get ahead.
这有什么大不了的啊
Okay, what's the big deal?
如果那能帮我多卖点药给医生
Look, if it helps me make a sale with a physician,
我觉得跟人家调情一下也无妨
I don't think it hurts to flirt a little.
比如他说笑话就笑一笑  碰碰他们的手臂
I mean, laugh at their joke, touch their arm,
下车前冷气开超强  激凸一下
maybe crank up the AC in the car beforehand, you know,
见医生管用
to wake up the girls.
可能在销售业界里有不同之处
Maybe it's different in the world of sales,
但在科学界  女性本来就已经
but it's already hard enough for women
很难被人认真公平对待了
to be taken seriously in science.
我本来还对参与文章这事挺激动
I was kind of excited about the article,
现在被你说得好难过
but now you're making me feel bad.
我觉得你想做什么就去做
No, I think you should do whatever you want.
当年如果有时尚杂志刊载女性科学家照片
You know, maybe if fashion magazines had female scientists in them,
说不定我也去当理论物理学家了
I would've become a theoretical physicist.
少在那边互相偷笑了
Stop smirking at each other.
多谢
Thank you.
是我该谢你
No, thank you.
送货员是我们国家贸易界的
Delivery men are the unsung foot soldiers
无名英雄
of our nation's commerce.
因为有你这样的人
It's because of people like you,
像我这样的人才可以尽少接触人
people like me can limit our human contact.
我很想与你握手  但你懂的...
I'd shake your hand, but, well, you know.
我不是送货员  我是名医生
I'm not a delivery man, I-I'm a doctor.
虽然我也常常
Although I do often deliver
亲自给病人送结果很不妙的活检报告
alarming biopsy results to my patients.
你真幽默
That's humorous.
呵呵
All right.
我猜你一定常让病人满身缝补[捧腹大笑]
Yeah, I-I bet you leave your patients in stitches.
我这也是幽默
That was also humorous.
呵呵
All right.
你手里拿着花
Are you bringing flowers to a patient
是为了安慰得了不治之症的病人吗
to cushion the blow of a terminal diagnosis?
刚才不是笑话
That wasn't a joke.
呵呵
All right.
这花是要送给一位
These are actually for a nice woman
打来我办公室推销的好姑娘
who makes sales calls to my office.
你知道有送货员可以代劳这种事吗
You know, they have delivery people that will do that for you.
我是想靠着
I was hoping to impress her
网上人肉她搜到的资料
by tracking her down on the Internet
直接来到她家门口给她一个惊喜
and then showing up unannounced at her door.
付出额外的努力
Making the extra effort.
给你按个赞
Good for you.
时间刚刚好  晚餐刚刚到
Great timing, food just got here.
-泰国菜吗  -是的
- Ooh, Siam Palace? - Yes.
-泰式炒面与鸡肉沙爹  -有的
- Uh, mee krob and chicken satay? - Yes.
-多加花生酱了吗  -没  我的给你好了
- Uh, extra peanut sauce? - No, but you can have mine.
好吧  也行
Eh, well, very well.
既然说到了分享你的东西
Oh, and on the topic of sharing things that are yours,
有个穿着绅士的访客
there is a gentleman caller
就在我们说话的这会  带着花找你未婚妻
bringing flowers to your fiancee as we speak.
什么
What?
你怎么不一进门就说呢
Why didn't you say that first?
那你为什么没多加花生酱呢
Why didn't you get extra peanut sauce?
要斗嘴谁怕谁
We can both play this game.
请问你有事吗
Can I help you?
你好
Oh, hi.
请问佩妮住这里吗
Uh, does Penny live here?
我能问为什么找她吗
May I ask why?
我是在我办公室认识她的  她对我抛媚眼
I-I met her at my office, she winked at me.
我来是希望跟她继续发展
I-I came hoping to initiate a romantic relationship.
我敢确定她没对你抛媚眼
Look, I'm pretty sure she didn't wink at you.
她绝对有
Oh, she did.
动作很勾人  像这样
Seductively, like this.
然后她摸了我的手臂足足两大秒
And then she touched my arm for two Mississippis.
像这样  一大秒  两...
Like, you know, one Mississippi, two...
我懂了  我懂了
I got it, I got it.
听我说
Listen, um...
我想这中间一定是有什么误会
I think there's been a misunderstanding.
佩妮是我的未婚妻
See, Penny is my fiancee.
真的吗
Really?
我从未看见她手上有戴订婚戒啊
I've never seen her wear an engagement ring.
真的吗
Really?
所以我可以推测
So, am I to presume
她挑逗我只是销售技巧的一种罢了
that her flirtation was just a sales technique?
应该是
I think so.
我什么时候才学精啊
When will I learn?
宠物店可爱女店员事件又重演了
It's just like the cute girl at the pet store all over again.
你说什么
Excuse me?
那个女孩摸了我的胳膊五大秒
Oh, uh, she touched my arm for five Mississippis,
我就花了两千美元买了一个鬣蜥的生态箱
and I bought a $2,000 iguana habitat.
不过她一直很忙  总是没时间来我家看
Which she was always too busy to come over and see.
这花你送给佩妮吧
You give these to Penny.
你是一个幸运的男人
You're, you're a lucky man.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉
Sorry.
这张卡片还是不要给她看了
You probably don't want her to see this.
里面有点过于"图文并茂"了
It's unnecessarily graphic.
等等  医生
Hold on, Doctor.
莱纳德  你的社交礼仪呢
Leonard, where are your social skills?
这位先生显然很难过
This man is clearly upset.
我们应该邀他进屋喝一杯热饮
We should invite him in for a hot beverage.
可是他想泡佩妮啊
He tried to score with Penny.
这俩以前也是啊  现在不还跟我们一起吃饭吗
So have these two, and they're having dinner with us.
今天工作如何
So, how was work today?
还行  你一定会很高兴得知
It was fine, but you'll be happy to know
性感科学家这篇文章取消了
they pulled the sexy scientists article.
发生什么事了
What happened?
我也不知道
I don't know.
杂志社就取消了照片拍摄
They just canceled the photo shoot
还说他们要重新考虑一下
and said they're rethinking it.
真是太遗憾了
Well, I'm really sorry,
但我认为这是一件好事
but I think it's for the best.
你会想人们关注你的科研成就
You want people focusing on your achievements,
而不是盯着某本杂志上的你的咪咪
not staring at your breasts in some magazine.
大概吧
I guess.
上杂志也没那么重要
It's really not that important.
喂  我眼睛在这呢
Hey, up here.
抱歉  说到了就忍不住看一下
Sorry, we're... we were talking about them.
听着  我本来不打算说的
So, look, I-I wasn't going to say anything,
但既然你对于文章被取消没意见
but since you seem to be okay with the article being canceled,
我要向你坦白件事
I have a little confession.
文章取消是因为我
I'm the reason it was pulled.
什么  怎么回事
What? How?
我给杂志社的编辑
I sent the editors of the magazine
发了一封严厉斥责的电邮
a pretty scathing e-mail.
艾米  你说了什么
Amy, what did you say?
我只是简单指出
I simply pointed out
他们绝对不会考虑做一篇关于
that they would never consider doing an article
男性科学家性感指数排名的文章
ranking male scientists on their sexuality,
更不会刊登他们不同程度宽衣解带的照片
let alone showing them in various stages of undress.
因为没人会想看奈尔·德葛拉司·泰森
Because no one wants to see Neil deGrasse Tyson
湿身在一辆保时捷的引擎盖上弯腰撅屁股
in a wet T-shirt, bent over the hood of a Porsche.
这没什么两样
Well, it doesn't make a difference,
反正杂志社也认为这的确不得体
because they agreed it was in bad taste,
现在你也这么认为  所以...
and now you agree, so...
艾米成功挽救大局
Amy saves the day.
错  事实是你嫉妒我
No, what happened was you got jealous,
所以你夺走了我宣传自己的机会
so you took away a chance for me to get some publicity.
但那是负面宣传
But it was bad publicity.
负不负面我说了算  关你屁事
That's for me to decide, not you.
我不同意
I disagree.
我认为你的所作所为  会影响我们所有女性科学家
As a female scientist, I think what you do affects all of us.
我认为你不喜欢人们展现性感的一面
And I think you don't like people expressing their sexuality
因为没人会要求你展现
because no one wants you to express yours.
艾米  非常对不起
Oh, Amy, I'm so sorry.
我说的太过分了
That was over the line.
祝你有个愉快的夜晚
You have a nice night.
拜托别走
Please don't go.
在我没有恶意攻击你前  错的人一直是你啊
Up until my vicious attack, you were the one in the wrong.
医生  请喝
Here you go, Doctor.
紅木槿活力茶  加一勺蜂蜜
Red Zinger with one teaspoon of honey.
谢谢
Thank you.
这《星际迷航》的杯子不错
Neat Star Trek mug.
其实我有一把来自老版电视剧的光枪
I actually have one of the phasers from the original TV show.
酷
Oh, cool.
你怎么搞到的
How'd you get that?
简单  吉恩·罗登贝瑞要做结扎手术
Oh, easy, Gene Roddenberry needed a vasectomy.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你居然切掉了《星际迷航》之父的输精管
You've snipped Gene Roddenberry's vas deferens?
是的
Yes.
他真是去了"前人未至之境"啊
Wow, he really went where no man has gone before.
源自《星际迷航：原初系列》开场导语中的一句短语
Where no man has gone before
我不喜欢吹嘘  但你们要知道
I don't like to brag, but, uh, you see,
我是专门帮明星们看尿路的医生
I'm kind of the doctor to the stars' urinary tracts.
你们想看詹姆斯·卡梅隆的肾结石吗
Uh, you, you want to see James Cameron's kidney stone?
好莱坞著名导演  因自编自导科幻电影《终结者》成名
也是《泰坦尼克号》与《阿凡达》的导演
他把石头排出之后超开心
He was so happy after he passed it,
还送了我一个终结者模型
he gave me a Terminator.
真是太不可思议了
That is amazing.
你从什么时候开始收藏的
How long have you been collecting?
从我小时候就开始了
Ever since I was a kid,
但之前都是玩票性质的
but, uh, I didn't really get serious
直到威廉·夏特纳膀胱感染  我才开始认真收藏
until William Shatner's bladder infection.
你又得到什么好处  快说说
What'd you get? What'd you get?
他说那是《星际迷航》里的毛毛球
Well, he said it was a tribble.
但其实也可能只是假发
It could be a toupee,
反正不管是哪样  都蛮酷的
but either way, it's pretty cool.
我超想去看你的藏品
I-I would love to see your collection.
随时欢迎
Anytime.
我有一些很酷的收藏
Uh, I've got some cool stuff.
我最初开始收藏时
When I first started,
我以为这会是结识女性的好方法
I thought it would be a good way to meet women,
但结果...你们懂的
but, well, you know...
-当然懂  -太懂了
- Sure. - Preach.
我能问你一个私人问题吗
Can I ask you a personal question?
问吧
Sure.
你和我基本上是一类人
Um, I mean, you're a guy like me,
你是怎么追到佩妮这类的上等妞
so how'd you get a girl like Penny?
就是...
Well, you know, just...
做自己  真的
being myself, really.
少来
Oh, please!
我来告诉他是怎么做到的
You know, I'll tell you how he did it.
绵延不绝  永无休止地纠缠
Implacable, relentless badgering.
用泌尿学术语来说
In urology terms,
他就像是耐药性葡萄球菌
he was a drug-resistant staph infection.
而她是摆脱不了葡萄球菌感染的尿道
And she was a urethra that could not shake him.
我可不会称自己是一种感染
I don't know that I'd call myself an infection.
英勇的男人回先为
A gallant man would defend
被称为"尿道"的未婚妻辩护
his fiancee for being called a urethra.
我们能换个话题吗
Can we please change the subject?
貌似天不遂人愿啊
Well, that didn't go your way.
乐维斯医生  你在这里做什么
Dr. Lorvis, what are you doing here?
其实我是来找你的
Uh, well, actually I came to see you.
是吗  为什么
Really? Why?
这问题问在点子上了
Ah, that's a good question.
貌似某人没有戴订婚戒
Apparently someone was being awfully flirty
而且整天跟人眉来眼去
while not wearing their engagement ring,
所以招惹了那人来到这里
causing another someone to show up here
因为他以为某人还单身
thinking the first someone might be available.
别说得这么复杂
Oh, God. Don't make it so hard on her.
某人指的是不忠的你
Look, the first someone is the deceitful you.
那人指的是
The second someone
可爱的乐维斯医生
is the delightful Dr. Lorvis.
这太尴尬了
Oh, this is very embarrassing.
乐维斯医生  真的很抱歉
Dr. Lorvis, I am so sorry.
我不是故意让你误会的
I did not mean to lead you on.
你把手放在我的胳膊上有两大秒呢
You touched my arm for two Mississippis.
怪不得你嘴里叨念着几大秒呢
That's why you were mumbling "Mississippi."
我们能借一步说话吗
Can we talk in private?
好的  走吧
Please, yes.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
你还经手过哪些名人的生殖器
So what other celebrity genitalia have you handled?
怎么回事
So, uh, what's the deal?
你上班就不戴订婚戒吗
You take off your ring when you go to work?
什么  没有这回事
What? No! No!
我就是戴在另外一只手上
I just put it on the other hand and...
再把戒指转个圈
turn it around.
然后把手放在口袋里
Keep that hand in my pocket.
为什么
Why?
这有什么好奇怪的
Well, what do you mean why?
如果医生认为我是单身
Look, I make more sales
我就能卖得更多
if these doctors think I'm single.
我做服务员的时候也做过同样的事
I did the same kind of thing as a waitress.
我想问的是  他在你的公寓里做什么
The real question is, what is he doing in your apartment?
他不高兴
Oh, he was upset.
谢尔顿就请他进屋喝热饮
So Sheldon invited him in for a hot beverage.
你没意见吗
You were okay with that?
有  我也很不高兴
No. I got upset!
然后谢尔顿也给了我一杯热饮
And Sheldon made me a beverage, too.
他突然出现在我门前
Okay, he just showed up at my door.
你不觉得有点奇怪吗
Don't you think that's a little weird?
是有点  不过他没有恶意
A little, but... he's basically harmless.
-他其实人挺好的  -好吧
- He's actually kind of a nice guy. - Okay.
总之  我的公司不允许我
Whatever, look, my company does not allow me
私下和医生有接触
to socialize with doctors outside of work.
你得赶走他
You got to get rid of him.
为什么要我去赶走他
Why am I the one that has to get rid of him?
我不能去  他是我最好的客户
I can't do it! He's my best client!
好吧  我来赶走他
All right, I'll get rid of him.
不过这次算你欠我的
But you owe me one.
我们要去奥利佛家欣赏他的收集品
Hey, we're going to Oliver's house to see his collection.
你要和我们一起去吗
You want to go with us?
好的
Yeah, sure.
你欠我的
You owe me.
我的上帝啊
Oh, my God!
莱纳德  我错了
Leonard, I was wrong.
天堂真的存在
Heaven does exist.
而天堂就在谢奥区
And it's in the basement of a urologist's house
一个泌尿科医生的地下室里
in Sherman Oaks.
欢迎来到我的"孤独堡垒"
Welcome to my Fortress of Solitude.
这是我摆脱
This is where I go to get away from...
我其他孤独的地方
all my other solitude.
这是复制品吧
Oh, come on. It's a replica.
原版
Original.
我想我刚背叛了我的妻子[高潮了]
Oh, I think I just cheated on my wife.
这是电影《地狱男爵》里的那把枪吗
The gun from Hellboy?
对
Yup.
你怎么得到的
How did you get it?
在一个拍卖上买回来的
Bought it at auction.
我还期望听到男主角
Oh, I was hoping for a juicy tidbit
朗·普尔曼的蛋蛋奇闻呢
about Ron Perlman's testicles.
奥利佛  我要去玩宾果了
Oliver! I'm going to play bingo!
好的妈妈  玩得开心
Okay, Mother. Have fun.
还和他妈妈住在一起
Still lives with his mom.
真可怜  对吧
Yikes, right?
我不知道该如何回答
Yeah, I'm not quite sure how to respond.
大金刚
Wow, Donkey Kong!
这是我小时候最爱的游戏
This-this was my game when I was a kid!
因为这是一个美丽的金发女孩
Because it's a story of a pretty blonde girl
被一个畸形的矮小男人不停追逐的故事吗
tirelessly pursued by a small, oddly-shaped man?
不是  因为我喜欢
No, because I liked it.
干嘛一说就炸毛
Well, now, don't get defensive.
你是有点畸形  不过你追到女孩了啊
You're oddly-shaped, but you got the girl.
我注意到莱纳德
So, I've noticed Leonard gets teased a lot
因为和佩妮的感情经常被取笑
about his relationship with Penny.
是的  如果你也想加入
Yes. If you'd like to join in,
我们一般以爱得好蠢注定失败为开头
the premise is their love seems unlikely and doomed to failure.
所以你觉得她很快会单身吗
So, you think she'll be single soon?
如果你想加入那个阵营
Oh, if you want to get in on the pool,
一切都太晚了
you're too late...
那里已经人满为患
All the squares have been purchased.
有意思
Interesting.
抱歉  我还有点事要办
Excuse me, I have to take care of something.
莱纳德  身为你的朋友
Leonard, as your friend I feel
-有件事我必须要告诉你  -什么
- I should tell you something. - What?
我还在气那个花生酱的事
I'm still upset about that peanut sauce.
请不要关门好吗
Oh, could you hold the door?
-好美的花  -谢谢
- Nice flowers. - Thank you.
是送给一个姑娘的
They're for a girl.
我要绵延不绝永无休止地纠缠她
Uh, I'm being implacable and relentless.
这姑娘真幸运啊
Isn't she lucky?
她给我的信号暧昧不明
She keeps sending me mixed signals.
但我...我想我俩追求的东西是一样的
But I-I think we both want the same thing.
追求什么
What's that?
无条件的爱
Unconditional love.
谁不想要这个呢
I guess that's all anybody wants.
没错
I guess so.
祝你成功
Well, I hope you get it.
一大秒  两大秒
One Mississippi, two Mississippi.
下一局我们换着头盔玩吧
Next game, let's switch helmets.
不要  我戴你那个头盔好蠢
No, I'd look silly in that helmet.
我不能收你的花
I-I can't take these.
为什么啊
Well, why not?
你我追求的目标一致
I mean, you want what I want.
我俩一起拥有过美好的两大秒时间
And we had two wonderful Mississippis.
那另一个姑娘怎么办
But what about the other girl?
好吧
Oh, right.
我会告诉她只做朋友
I'll tell her we should just be friends.
乐维斯医生
Dr. Lorvis?
佩妮  我们还是当朋友吧
Penny, we should just be friends.
你高兴了吧
Happy?
你觉得这玩意会咬人吗
You think he bites?
把你的头伸进去试试看吧
Stick your hand in there and find out.
上次在动物乐园看山羊时你就骗过我
You fooled me with that goat at the petting zoo.
这次休想再骗到我
You will not fool me again.
乐维斯医生去哪儿了
I wonder where Dr. Lorvis is.
他离开好一会儿了
He's been gone a while.
也许是在陪他妈咪玩宾果游戏吧
Maybe he's playing bingo with his mommy.
都成年了还这么粘父母  真可悲
It's sad how some guys can't cut the apron strings.
你说这话是特么在逗我吧
Okay, now you're messing with me.
各位  我们被锁这里了
Uh, guys, we're locked in here.
今天的好事真是一件接一件啊
Oh, this day just keeps getting better!
所以你就把他们留在家里玩游戏吗
So, you just left them alone playing games in your house?
他们玩得挺开心的
Well, they seemed happy and...
这样我们也有更多时间
I thought that would give me time
能更深入了解彼此
for you and I to get to know each other better.
这都是遇见你之前的事了
That was before we met.
谁人没有过去呢
We all have a past.
医生  你要知道你的所作所为
Doc, you've got to see what you're doing
实在有点小吓人
is-is a little creepy.
我跟踪西格妮·韦弗进厕所时
You sound just like Sigourney Weaver
她也说了同样的话
when I followed her into a restroom.
你不能一遇到对你好的姑娘
Okay, you can't just go chasing after
就追着人家走
every girl who's nice to you.
谢尔顿可不是这么说的
Well, that's not what Sheldon says.
他这人看着挺会泡妞的啊
And he seems to know his way around the ladies.
莱纳德  猜猜谁回来了  乐维斯医生哦
Hey, Leonard. Guess who's back! Dr. Lorvis!
你想和我们一起玩吗
Yeah. You care to join us?
什么
What?!
你把他们锁在你的地下室里了
You locked them in your basement?!
他们没有被锁啊
Well, they're, they're not locked in.
门只是卡住了而已
The door just sticks.
好吧  那要怎么才能把门打开
Okay, so how do they unstick it?
必须用钥匙
They'd need the key.
够了
Okay.
不行  够了
Nope. That's it.
我们马上去你家
We are gonna go over there right now.
把他们放出来
And you are going to let them out.
-三大秒  四大秒  -快走
- Three Mississippi, four Mississippi... - Move it!
太好了  你在这里
Oh, good, you're here.
艾米  我真的很抱歉
Amy, I am so sorry.
那个等等再说  这疯子把
That has to wait. This weirdo locked
-那几个男生都锁在他家地下室了  -什么
- the guys up in his basement. - What?!
-她人看着不错  叫啥名啊  -赶紧走
- She seems nice. Who's she? - Just walk.
你一定可以的
You can do this.
还剩一个梯子了
One ladder left!
-好耶  -太棒了
- Oh-ho! Yeah! - Yes!
下一关
Next level!
-莱纳德  你还好吗  -超级棒
- Leonard, are you okay? - Better than okay.
我正处于游戏人生的最巅峰
I am having the game of my life!
乐维斯医生  你不是有话要说吗
Dr. Lorvis, isn't there something you want to say?
对哦
Yes.
我很抱歉把你们锁在我家里
I'm very sorry for locking you in my home.
没错  这也太不够意思了
Yeah, that was very uncool.
抓那个锤子  抓那个锤子
Get the hammer! Get the hammer!
成了
Got it.
好了  莱纳德  我们回家吧
Okay, Leonard, let's go!
再等一下下
J-Just hang on!
那个  你们等待的时候
Well, while we wait,
想不想看看托比·马奎尔的前列腺超声波扫描
would you like to see Tobey Maguire's prostate sonogram?
好吧
Sure. Yeah.
剧透一下
Oh, spoiler alert.
他完全是想太多
Uh, he was worried about nothing.
此为著名天文学家奈尔·德葛拉司·泰森
露胸+保时捷照效果图